#### Suresh Thoosimuthu

Mail ID: Sureshsafety2009@gmail.com Contact Number: +91 8940404515

## Objective:

Safety Officer's with 11 years of experience in Oil & Gas / Refinery / Petrochemical / Chemical as a primary objective is to ensure the safety and welfare of the resource - Manual / Equipment in the organization. This will be achieved by implementing occupational safety and health programs that is geared towards protecting the benefits of the company's assets. Applying knowledge & experience to train the workforces on safe work practice in the worksites and promoting zero accident culture in the workplaces. Seeking the position of a Health and Safety Professional in a reputed organization where I can provide my expertise in analyzing the HSE protocols, Pro-Actively contribute and promote healthy and safe workplace in the organization.

#### Key Deliverables:

- Approved by KOC and KNPC as safety Officer.
- Conducting On-Site inspection on daily basis for ensuring safe work & Initiate for immediate corrective action for any Complex issues.
- Applying / Monitoring/Maintaining OSHA standards / Compliance with OSHA policies & procedures.
- Supporting management in full filling of safety Obligations / Setting goals for safety matters.
- Familiar with complete documentation work related to HSE.
- Conducting Fitness to service inspection for equipment's.
- Successfully completed shutdown works in Gathering Center inside KOC Premises
- Familiar with firefighting equipment's.
- > Authorized gas tester for Confined space entry.

## **Employment Highlights:**

Period of Service									
From	То	No of Years	Designation	Client	Projects Handled				
From June 2011 to till date Explomo Technical Services Pte Ltd, Kuwait									
May 2017	July 2018	1.2 year	Safety Officer	KOC / Wood / Explomo	UXO Program Phase- 1 for North and South Kuwait Oilfields				
August 2016	April 2017	.10 year	Sr.Safety Officer	KOC / Worley Parsons / UDC	Sulaibiya, Braine pumping Facilities				
June 2013	July 2016	3.1 year	Safety Officer	KOC / Worley Parsons / Saipem	Booster station (BS- 171) at KOC West Kuwait				
June 2011	May 2013	02 year	Safety Officer	KOC / Flour / Hyundai	Installation of Low Sulphur Fuel Oil, Fuel Gas and Gas Oil pipelines from Mina Al-Ahmadi to Sabiya and Doha Power Stations, Kuwait				
From November 2007 to June 2010 , Gulf Spic general trading & Contracting company W.L.L, Kuwait									
June 2010	May 2011	1 year	Safety Officer	KOC / AMEC / Saipem	Installation of New Compressors at GC-07, GC-08 & GC-21, Kuwait				
Sep 2009	May 2010	09 Months	Safety Officer	SKEC/ AMEC/ KOC	Construction of New Gathering Centre (GC-24) at KOC North Kuwait Site				

June 2009	August 2009	03 Months	Safety Officer	PIC	Revamping works of Urea plant for PIC, KUWAIT(Shut Down)
April 2008	May 2009	1.1 year	Safety Supervisor	Shaw Group, UK / Fluor/ DOW-PIC/ Equate	Ethyl Benzene Styrene & Monomer Plant in Equate (OL2K EBSM Project)
Nov 2007	April 2008	06 Months	Safety Supervisor	Fluor/ DOW-PIC/ Equate	Construction of Mechanical 1 Infrastructure Facilities for OL2K Projects in Equate (OL2K M1 Project)

# UXO Program Phase- 1 for North and South Kuwait Oilfields

The Scope of Works comprise the activities related to site Ground
Truthing and Utility survey, Topographic and Geophysical survey, Clearance and Disposal
of UXO, pre-site characterization, excavation, mixing, loading, transportation and disposal/ (filling & compaction) of oily contaminated soil from the identified features to landfill facility.

## **RESPONSIBILITIES/ DELIVERABLES:-**

- Responsible to assist the HSE team in their duties as Pro-Active in safe work environment.
- Conducting EOD/UXO awareness training to all employees.
- Involved in safeguarding against exposure hazards and precautions against H2S exposure.
- Conducting toolbox talk weekly & as per task required.
- Monitor all the job activity at the site to ensure safety compliance.
- Implementing HSE policies & Procedures.
- Implementing the JSA / JHA / SOC / SVV & TBT & explaining the importance of the same. Following Up to application.
- Evaluate the JSA / RA for the work involved prepared by Supervisor / Foremen. Flowingly assist in Risk management & Hazards Identification involved in the work
- Increasing awareness on Health / Safety within organization to prevention of injury for personnel / equipment damage.
- Supporting Sr. HSE officer in preparing materials for HSE In-House training.
- Advising persons for safe work based on JSA for the particular work.
- Conducting monthly inspection program of site equipment & Firefighting equipment to ensure safe Operation.
- Assist in conducting monthly evacuation drill in the particular groups in order to keep them update & to ensure they have proper knowledge regarding HSE procedure
- To record / maintain a database of all inspections conducted to follow Up / Identify corrective actions.
- Prepare & Submit daily safety reports / inspection reports.
- Recording / Tracking of PTW to be applicable for obtaining permit & the same producing for auditing.
- Managing all commercial / Technical documents for issuing by ensuring accuracy of all documents.
- Reviewing lifting Plan & permit to work before any complex lift.
- Verifying to confirm that all lifting equipment Operators are trained, Competent / Certified.
- Analyzing Incident / Accident reports. For documentation & the same to producing.
- Controlling the site traffic by installing of proper traffic control Sings / Other safety promotion Posters inside the working premises.

### **EDUCATION DETAILS:**

- Diploma in Industrial Safety from the Institute of Management & Technology, [ 2003 ] Indian Institute of Management & Technology, Chennai
- First Aid and Emergency Course (EMS), Kuwait [ 2012 ] Kuwait Red Crescent Society, Kuwait
- Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.) Chemistry [ 2002 ]
   Manonmaniam Sundaranar University, Tirunelveli

#### ADDITIONAL TRAINING / CERTIFICATIONS:

- > KOC Induction Center Training for Confined Space Entry, PTW, H2S, UXO&EOD, SOC
- Safe Working Procedure
- > Fall Protection
- Work Permit System
- Entry into the "Confined Space"
- Working at Heights
- Scaffolding Safety
- > Fire & Safety
- Hand and Power Tools
- Rigging
- ➤ Hot Work
- ➤ LOTO and Material Handling
- Use of Personal Protective Equipment
- First Aid
- Fire Fighting and Emergency Preparedness
- Electrical Safety
- Explosive Ordnance Disposal Training

#### **PERSONAL DETAILS:**

FATHER NAME : E.THOOSIMUTHU

MARTIAL STATUS : MARRIED
DATE OF BIRTH : 05/JUNE/1981

LANGUAGES KNOWN : ENGLISH / HINDI / TAMIL

COMMUNICATION ADDRESS : 336 B WEST STRET

THANAKKAR KULAM [PO]

RADHA PURAM [TK], TIRUNELVELI [DT]

627 116

PASS PORT DETAILS : L 3818554

PLACE OF ISSUE : KUWAIT

DATE OF ISSUE : 11/11/2013

DATE OF EXPIRY : 10/11/20123

CIVIL ID : 281060507536

## **DECLARATION:**

HERE BY I DECLARE THAT THE ABOVE MENTION STATEMENTS ARE TRUE AND BEST OF MY KNOWLEDGE.

Date:

Location:

Suresh Thoosimuthu